Man is wolf to man.
Plautus, "Asinaria"
Watch out
for wild boars
Koenji! What the hell
are you doing up there?!
The truly superior belong
in high places, don't they?
H-Hey!
What the hell is that freak doing?
Damn it. I'll call him back.
Did you hurt it?
No wonder. It's an unfamiliar mountain path,
nine kilometers each way.
This idiot's dragging us down.
I thought he was supposed
to be our group leader!
Just leave us out of your failure, would you?
Why can't I do this right, either?
C'mon, hang tight.
You can lean on me.
I'll see if I can fetch Koenji.
This is going to make you both late, too.
Letting you aggravate your injury will
make things worse for us on test day.
Right, Ayanokoji?
Sorry, you two.
What are you doing, Koenji?
If it isn't little boy Ayanokoji.
As you can see, I was enjoying
a bit of sport with this boar.
No need to worry.
I'll return later.
Or was there something you needed me for?
It's about the day of the exam.
I'd like you to help the group.
I've heard enough of that for a lifetime.
But it's not you who dictates my behavior...
It is I.
Oh, I see.
What do you see?
The true identity of the one who
got Dragon Boy to settle down.
You do an excellent job feigning ignorance,
but the passion in your trembling
arm tells me all I need to know.
I think you're seeing
things that aren't there.
No need to worry.
I have no plans of revealing your secret.
Regardless, I intend to follow
my heart at all times.
It doesn't seem like anyone can get to him.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
This is great!
What the hell kind of meat is this?
They got an unexpected delivery of boar meat.
Whoa, so it's like game meat?!
G-Game?
But who brought the boar in?
That's...
Probably some local hunter?
Excuse me.
Did you drop this?
Oh, hey, I did!
Thanks so much.
I really could have lost this, you know?
I can't believe you're the one who found it!
You know who I am?
You stood out in the relay
with Horikita-senpai.
And Miyabi—Oh, you wouldn't
know him by that name...
President Nagumo has his eye on you, too.
Running is the only real skill I have.
Do you think there's a way to get
Nagumo-senpai's eye off of me?
Maybe you could beat him at something?
I'd love to see Miyabi
knocked down a peg, myself.
I see.
I suppose that is one option.
Oh, jeez, it was just a joke!
Would it be a problem for you
if Nagumo-senpai were beaten?
Are you being serious?
You don't seem as enamored with
Nagumo Miyabi as the other second-years.
Well, aren't you forward?
I have a history with Miyabi, you could say.
Fine.
As thanks for returning my charm,
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
Thank you very much.
What I'd like to know
is what happened when the
girls divided into groups.
Hey, Ishizaki. You got a minute?
Hell no.
There's just two days to the exam.
We're gonna be in trouble at this rate.
Oh, shut up.
I don't give a damn if I'm expelled.
I played soccer in elementary
and middle school.
The hell's that got to do with anything?
It was the kind of school that
made it to nationals every year,
and while I wasn't exactly
an ace, I was pretty good.
You just wanna brag about how great you are?
But while everyone else was aiming
passionately for nationals,
I found myself feeling detached from it all.
Like I didn't belong there.
But you're not in the soccer club now.
Yeah, see, I had a tendency
to hide out and smoke.
So they caught you and kicked you out?
Nah, I was really good at hiding.
But I felt this kind of
alienation the whole time.
So I quit soccer.
I regret it sometimes, though.
I look at the guys in the
soccer club and think,
"maybe I could've been part of that."
What about you guys?
What've you got in your pasts?
Huh? I...
I don't have squat.
I've done nothing but
study since I was a child.
I was awful at sports,
and I couldn't see the point
in trying to get better.
And that's why you're
so good at school stuff?
Yeah. I thought my academic skills were
good enough to get me into Class A.
But I ended up in Class D.
I resented that.
But next thing I know,
my polar opposite, Sudo,
has been helping the class
way more than I have.
Right now, I feel... just like I did at
the island exam and the sports festival.
I'm completely mortified.
Hey, man...
I'm sorry, Ishizaki.
I'm supposed to be your leader,
but I'm hardly acting like a role model.
What a load of crap.
Don't apologize for that.
I mean, sure, it ticks me off
when you order me around...
But it's not like anyone else
was gonna take responsibility
for this bunch of misfits.
Ishizaki...
Being in a group of ruffians
isn't as bad as you'd think.
Who're you calling a ruffian?!
He's not wrong.
We're kinda trash.
You know it.
Right?
Family!
Go rest, damn it.
But...
It'll be worse for us if
you can't run on test day.
In exchange, you'd better
carry us on the written exam.
Score 120% or something!
Commendable behavior, my delinquent friend.
Shut up! You wanna die today, Koenji?
Everyone. Regarding tomorrow's marathon...
I thought up a plan I'd
like to share with you.
A plan?
Everyone in the group has a minimum
distance they have to run in the relay.
But as long as that's achieved,
there's nothing forbidding certain students
from running the excess distance.
So you want to let the best
runners run most of the course?
Yes.
Of course, it's a mountain path.
It'll be asking a lot of you guys, but...
Fine by me.
I'll run all your extra distance.
I'm down for that, too.
I can handle some distance running.
Thank you both.
How about you, Albert?
Well, he's fast enough,
but he's weirdly lacking in stamina.
Sorry.
He's amazing at dashing down
a steep decline, though.
I'll do the best I can, too.
Just leave it to me!
You're sure, Kiyotaka?
What'd you say?
Just don't get your hopes up too high.
He's down for the plan.
The rest is up to Koenji.
Though I doubt you'll be able
to convince him to care.
We'll just have to wing it there.
Our leader's got his work cut out for him.
Mii-chan, you're in
Ichinose-san's group, right?
You're the only one from our class, aren't you?
Hey, guys. How's it going?
Is that hard?
Sudo-kun, you never change.
No, everyone's been really nice...
You all seem to be doing well.
If you need any help, just ask, okay?
Thank you, Hirata-kun!
Why are you sitting there crying?
I-I'm not crying!
Are you worried about tomorrow's test?
It's Horikita-kun I'm worried for.
Does that man ever worry about anything?
Horikita-kun... has been fighting
on his own all this time.
Because the rest of us always drag him down.
He's always sacrificed himself
to protect the rest of us.
Even now, he's carrying the fight with
Nagumo-kun entirely on his own shoulders...
But we can't do anything to help him.
You're really not having
any problems of your own?
You don't give up, do you?
It's really nothing.
Just forget this happened.
Hashimoto and Ryuen?
It's hard to tell what they're
saying at this distance.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Mixed Training Camp: Last Day
Test 1: Zen
The day of the four tests arrived.
Test 2: Written Exam
In the written exam,
Yukimura carried his weight.
Test 3: Speech
The speech exam also went smoothly.
But the real deciding factor
would be, as expected...
Test 4: Marathon
the marathon, where placement
would make a huge difference.
Yukimura's Group
First Runner: Sumida
Ichi Springs
Oshin River
Second Runner: Moriyama
Third Runner: Totsuka
Usagimori Jizo  Mt. Rea Summit
Fourth Runner: Hashimoto
Fifth Runner: Albert
Albert!
Sixth Runner: Ishizaki
Seventh Runner: Yukimura
Yukimura!
You made me run extra, so you'd
better give this all you've got!
I will!
Sorry!
We're still good.
You did well.
Leave the rest to me.
Well, then...
Perhaps I'll work up a bit of a sweat.
You all did well over the eight
days of this training camp.
The average score was
better than last year's.
All of the boys' groups
exceeded the borderline,
so no one will be expelled.
Hey.
I always knew we'd get it done.
Family.
Incidentally, the highest overall
score came from Class 3-A,
Horikita Manabu's group.
You did it, Horikita.
Congratulations, Horikita-senpai.
That's very impressive.
It seems you lost, Nagumo.
Well... that's up for debate.
Meanwhile, in the girls' groups...
I'm afraid there was one group
that fell under the borderline.
The group led by Ikari Momoko of Class 3-B.
What the hell did you do, Nagumo?!
Please calm down, Fujimaki-senpai.
They're still announcing results.
Why is Fujimaki-senpai of Class A so upset?
The group leader was in Class B.
The issue isn't the leader,
but who she's taking with her.
Unfortunately, Ikari will be expelled,
along with a student she designates
as sharing responsibility.
Ikari, who do you designate?
Who do you think?
The one who disrupted the
harmony of our group...
Tachibana Akane-san!
It was all a trap by Nagumo.
The duel was a distraction
from his real objective.
His target from the start
was Tachibana Akane.
Nagumo used girls loyal to
his faction to create a group
specifically designed to fall under
the borderline and take Tachibana out.
Tachibana, why didn't you ask me for help?
Because...
I knew I would be a burden to you.
I'm sorry.
Friendship is a beautiful thing.
Or should I call it "love"?
Tell me all about how you feel right now.
Are you more annoyed than
you've ever been before?
Why is Tachibana the one you targeted?
I was just dying to see your
face when I got rid of her.
That indulgence of your curiosity
has cost you something dear, Nagumo.
Even if we did things differently,
I still trusted you.
And I'm choosing to throw
that trust in your face.
I'll expel as many people as I need to.
That's how things are meant
to be done at this school.
Nagumo's maliciousness won the day.
But I doubt Horikita Manabu considered
Tachibana an indispensable pawn.
You're talking as if Tachibana
is going to be expelled.
Sir.
There's something I wish
to spend points to buy.
W-Wait, Horikita-kun!
Wow, I thought we'd come out of this even.
You're really going to spend all those
points to save Tachibana-senpai?
Please, don't! I've brought this on myself!
Do you mind, everyone?
Are you sure about this?
You're effectively handing
over your standing as Class A.
Only until I take it back, though.
Horikita-kun...
Well, that's just fine by me.
I guess Nagumo isn't the
only one with two faces.
It's absolutely unbelievable!
I can't believe he cooked
up a crazy plan like that.
If I were that Ikari girl,
I'd never volunteer to be expelled!
Well, Ikari won't actually be expelled.
How come?
For the same reason as Tachibana Akane.
She'll be saved from expulsion through the
expenditure of large amounts of points.
Nagumo would have agreed to cover that.
Does that mean Nagumo-senpai
lost a lot from this, too?
The second-years are a monolith under Nagumo.
They can easily afford it
by pooling their resources.
But Horikita Manabu has to pay
with only one class's funds,
so it's a more serious blow.
It's such a reckless way to fight.
That's how Nagumo Miyabi fights, I suppose.
You didn't forget anything, did you?
I said I checked. Just trust me!
I guess we'd better split up.
Wait, tell me one more thing!
If I ended up in the same situation...
What do you think you would—
I wouldn't let you be expelled.
I'd do whatever it takes.
What was to follow
was a series of expulsions from
Advanced Nurturing High School
involving all class years.